export const jsQuizz = {
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Which of the following is used in React.js to increase performance?",
        choices: [
          "Virtual DOM",
          "Original DOM",
          "Both A and B",
          "None of the above",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Virtual DOM",
      },
      {
        question:
          " Are the negative values allowed in padding property?",
        choices: [
          "Yes",
          "No",
          "Can't say",
          "May be",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "No",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The CSS property used to specify the transparency of an element is -",
        choices: [
          "opacity",
          "filter",
          "visibility",
          "overlay",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "opacity",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the purpose of the HTML <head> element?",
        choices: [
          "To define the main content of the page",
          "To include metadata about the document",
          "To create a header section for the page",
          "To specify the layout of the page",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "To include metadata about the document",
      },
      {
        question:
          " Which of the following values is not a valid color representation in CSS?",
        choices: [
          "#123456",
          "rgb(255, 0, 128)",
          "color: blue;",
          "hsl(120, 100%, 50%)",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "color: blue;",
      },
      {
        question:
          " How can you convert a string to an integer in JavaScript?",
        choices: [
          "parseInt(string)",
          "string.toInt()",
          "toInteger(string)",
          "convertToInt(string)",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "parseInt(string)",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the purpose of the React Fragment?",
        choices: [
          "To create fragments of code for better organization",
          "To group multiple components without adding extra nodes to the DOM",
          "To define conditional rendering",
          "To create animations",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "To group multiple components without adding extra nodes to the DOM",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the purpose of the key prop in React when rendering a list of elements?",
        choices: [
          "It defines the color of the element",
          "It specifies the position of the element",
          "It helps React identify which items have changed, are added, or are removed",
          "It is used to set the font size of the element",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "It helps React identify which items have changed, are added, or are removed",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the correct way to comment out multiple lines in HTML?",
        choices: [
          "<!-- This is a comment -->",
          "/* This is a comment */",
          " // This is a comment //",
          " <# This is a comment #>",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "<!-- This is a comment -->",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In CSS, what does the position: relative; property do?",
        choices: [
          "Positions an element relative to its normal position",
          "Aligns an element to the right",
          "Fixes an element to the viewport",
          "Centers an element horizontally",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Positions an element relative to its normal position",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the purpose of the try...catch statement in JavaScript?",
        choices: [
          "To define a function",
          "To handle exceptions or errors",
          "To create a loop",
          "To declare a variable",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "To handle exceptions or errors",
      },
      {
        question:
          " How do you add a new element to the end of an array?",
        choices: [
          "array.push()",
          "array.add()",
          "array.append()",
          "array.insert()",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "array.push()",
      },
      {
        question:
          " In HTML, what is the purpose of the <mark> element?",
        choices: [
          "To highlight text",
          "To create a hyperlink",
          "To define a navigation menu",
          "To display code",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "To highlight text",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In React, what is Redux used for?",
        choices: [
          "To manage component styling",
          "To manage state in a predictable way",
          "To handle HTTP requests",
          " To create animations",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "To manage state in a predictable way",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which hook is used for performing side effects in a functional component?",
        choices: [
          "useEffect",
          "useEffectEffect",
          "useSideEffect",
          "sideEffect",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "useEffect",
      },
      {
        question:
          " How can you prevent the default behavior of an event in JavaScript?",
        choices: [
          "event.prevent()",
          "event.default()",
          "event.preventDefault()",
          "preventDefault(event)",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "event.preventDefault()",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which HTML tag is used to define the navigation menu in a webpage?",
        choices: [
          "<menu>",
          "<nav>",
          "<navbar>",
          "<navigation>",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "<nav>",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What does the CSS property z-index control?",
        choices: [
          "Element visibility",
          "Element rotation",
          "Element stacking order",
          "Element border thickness",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Element stacking order",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which CSS pseudo-class is used to select and style the last child element of its parent?",
        choices: [
          ":last",
          ":nth-child(1)",
          ":last-child",
          ":only-child",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: ":last-child",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the result of the expression typeof undefined in JavaScript?",
        choices: [
          "undefined",
          "null",
          "string",
          "object",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "undefined",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What does the HTML <img> tag attribute 'alt' represent?",
        choices: [
          "Alignment of the image",
          "Attribute of the image",
          "Altitude of the image",
          "Alternative text for the image",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Alternative text for the image",
      },
      {
        question: "What is ReactJS?",
        choices: [
          "Server-side framework",
          "User Interface framework",
          "both a and b",
          "None of the above",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "User Interface framework",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Identify the one which is used to pass data to components from outside",
        choices: ["Render with arguments", "setState", "PropTypes", "props"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "props",
      },
      {
        question: "What is the result of the expression 5 + '3' in JavaScript?",
        choices: ["53", "8", "35", "Error"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "53",
      },
      {
        question: "What is Babel?",
        choices: [
          "JavaScript interpreter",
          "JavaScript transpiler",
          "JavaScript compiler",
          "None of the above",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "JavaScript compiler",
      },
    ],
  };

  export const resultInitialState={
    score:0,
    correctAnswer:0,
    wrongAnswers:0,
  }